Tor Francis

Philadelphia, PA | 678-790-2697 | torfrancis447@gmail.com linkedin.com/tor-francis | Portfolio | dev.to/torfrancis447

SUMMARY

A highly motivated and natural people-person software developer with experience designing and developing full-stack and front-end applications in Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and React. Proven ability to provide excellent end-users experience with years of experience in sales and customer service.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Material UI, Nextjs, Bootstrap, SQL, NextJs, AWS S3, Sqlite3, Git, Visual Studio Code, REST, APIs, Bcrypt, TailwindCSS, MongoDB, Node.js

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Moodify - Github

An app for user's find music that matches their mood on Spotify

- Front-end-only project using HTML/CSS/vanilla JavaScript that accesses data from Spotify API to query playlists.
- Implemented toggleable CSS mode and In browser music player.

Gamer's Paradise - Github | Demo

An app where users can keep track of games they would like to play

- Created a React app using Bootstrap for the CSS and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized a frontend API to fetch Video game data to be able to search for games currently on the market.

Dev Hunt - Github

A job board app for candidates looking for developer jobs and companies looking to hire talent

- Implemented AWS S3 for document storage and Image storage.
- A full-stack application that follows RESTful API conventions including Authentication and Authorization.
- Used front-end API for email notifications.

EXPERIENCE

Ainley's Search Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruiter

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Consulted with clients to obtain a precise understanding of the technical job description and requirements to fill positions with high-quality candidates in the manufacturing industry.
- Contributed to the acquisition of a major chemical Manufacturer.

Frank's Recruitment Group

Philadelphia, PA

Recruitment consultant

01/2022 - 05/2022

- Participate in business development to identify top accounts, target skill sets, and assess clients' ServiceNow needs.
- Negotiating employment offers for candidates in the ServiceNow industry.
- Assisted in the successful placement of candidates into client position vacancies.

Extra Space Storage District Team Lead

Philadelphia, PA

• Managed 7 different properties with up to 800 concurrent customers

05/2016 - 01/2022

- I had a to a second CO in the late of the control o
- Led a team of 20 individuals to drive revenue and key performance indicators for a Fortune 500 company
- Exceeded expectation of property occupancy 4 years in a row and maintained occupancy rate of over 90% for 1 year.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Philadelphia, PA

Full Stack Web Development program

Rigorous coursework learning and applying the fundamentals of Javascript, React, SQL, and Ruby on Rails.

10/ 2022 - 03/2023

Penn State University

Philadelphia, PA 05/ 2018